Guide to the photograph album Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s AD.MC.014
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s
1916-19
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Antiquariat Inlibris (1883-present)
AD.MC.014
1 Linear Feet - Album (22 × 17.5 cm) with 150 silver print gelatin, albumen and carbon print photographs
Album (22 × 17.5 cm) with 150 silver print gelatin, albumen and carbon print photographs mounted in a writing journal made by Eyre & Spottiswoode in London. 55 ff. The photographs vary in sizes with the smallest measuring 5.5 × 5 cm and the largest 10.5 × 8 cm. Soft maroon cloth boards with the original endpapers and gilt edges.
This photograph album contains a collection of photographs of scenes in Egypt compiled by an unidentified Royal Flying Corps member in 1916–19. The photographer was quite possibly assigned to the Number 14 Squadron that assisted T. E. Lawrence in the Arab Revolt (1916–18). The album also yields first-hand snapshot images of World War I aircraft, including several crashed aeroplanes. Interesting is the photograph of a destroyed tank, since only a few of these were deployed in the Middle East during WWI The final 58 photographs show the compiler's home life in Great Britain.
Box AD_MC_014
Arrangement
The collection was processed as it was received.
Biographical / Historical
This photograph album contains a collection of photographs of scenes in Egypt compiled by an unidentified Royal Flying Corps member in 1916–19. The photographer was quite possibly assigned to the Number 14 Squadron that assisted Lawrence of Arabia in the Arab Revolt (1916–18).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions at akkasah.org. For access to physical album contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Scope and Contents
Text from catalogue: Many photographs in this album depict daily life in Egypt, such as women fetching water from the Nile and carrying it in large terracotta pots and a young shepherd boy assisting his father near the pyramids. Most interesting is a man pressing garments by foot with a hot iron, ploughing crops with an ox-driven wood sledge, and other field work. Great use is made of various forms of carts, from selling tea or snacks, to general travel. Camels also prove most efficient for conveyance, as caravans cross the desert, the men leading afoot, and others are heavily laden with building materials. Also shown are pastoralist nomads, Bedouins fabricating a tent, and Berbers leading camel. Especially rare, however, are the images of European women donning forms of the so-called burqa in a fashionable manner, with jewelry, lace embellishments and classic heels. The album also yields first-hand snapshot images of World War I aircraft, including several crashed airplanes. Interesting is the photograph of a destroyed tank, since only a few of these were deployed in the Middle East during WWI. The final 58 photographs show the compiler's home life in Great Britain.
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in December 2015.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Album purchased from Antiquariat INLIBRIS, Rathausstraße 19, 1010 Wien, Austria in 2015.
Egypt; Military/Soldiers; Airplanes; Photographic Prints; Air Force; Antiquariat Inlibris (1883-present)
- The front cover of the album 'Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s'., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr01; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Egypt; English Writing
- The inside front cover of the album 'Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr02; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Egypt
- The inside front cover of the album 'Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr03; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- A handwritten note on the inside cover of the album 'Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr04; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  English Writing; Egypt
- The title page for the album 'Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s' produced by Eyre and Spottiswoods, Great New Street, London, E.C., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr05; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  English Writing; London, England, UK; Egypt; Art; Printed Materials
- The back of the title page of 'Royal Flying Corps - Egypt in the 1910s'., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr06; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr07; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_afr08; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Clockwise from top left: Feluccas on a river, the Sphinx, the Pyramid of Khafre, and people in the street., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Men; Regional/National Dress; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Egypt; Palm Trees; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Camels; Animals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Cemeteries
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Street scenes., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Group Portraits; Men; Donkeys; Animals; Women; Workers; Architecture; Buildings; Egypt; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Umbrellas/Parasols; Street Vendors
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Clockwise from top left: a woman, a man next to a camel, street vendors and women at a well. Original text "men lounging in the street and women cooking.", Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Women; Regional/National Dress; Tents; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Men; Boys; Children; Camels; Animals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Hats; Street Vendors; Turbans; Water; Niqab/Burqa
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Three views of the funerary complexes of Mamluk Amir Qurqumas and Mamluk Sultan al-Ashraf Inal., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Mosques; Religious Sites; Deserts; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Camels; Regional/National Dress; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums; Funerary complexes of Emir Qurqumas and Sultan al-Ashraf Inal
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Kasr el Nil bridge, houseboats on the Nile, and men gathered in the street., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Bridges; Statues/Sculptures; Palm Trees; Canals; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Men; Crowds; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Street Lamps; Umbrellas/Parasols; Turbans; Hats
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: A boy working at a cobblers, children next to swings and a street vendor., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Boys; Children; Men; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Workers; Street Vendors; Shops; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Pottery; Turbans
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Two men riding camels, the Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza, and a sailboat on a river., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Egypt; Men; Camels; Animals; Deserts; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Two veiled women with a man sitting on a carriage, two men sitting mill and people in a funeral procession., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Agriculture/Farms; Carriages/Coaches; Funeral Proceedings; Flags; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Jewelry; Donkeys; Animals; Boys; Children; Arabic Writing; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Coffins/Caskets; Niqab/Burqa; Transportation
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Three views of a desert landscape with a stone walls and a caravan of camels., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Camels; Animals; Deserts; Men; Individual Portraits; Streets/Roads; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Two images of men wearing pith helmets in the desert and three men wearing pith helmets with a man wearing a turban and sitting on a camel., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Tents; Deserts; Camels; Animals; Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Smoking; Cigarettes; Food; Clocks/Watches; Turbans
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: a stone structure, a soldier outside a structure, and a herd of donkeys with people in the background., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Buildings; Men; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Donkeys; Animals; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Military/Soldiers
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Portraits of men wearing pith helmets and camels with a tent in the background., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Camels; Dogs; Animals; Men; Uniforms; Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Agriculture/Farms; Tents; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Canes/Walking Sticks; Pottery
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Three views of cattle pulling a plough., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Agriculture/Farms; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Group Portraits; Palm Trees; Uniforms; Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Two views of cattle pulling a plough and two men sitting on the ground sifting crops., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Agriculture/Farms; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Palm Trees; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Top and bottom images: Men sifting crops. Central image: Two men wearing pith helmets using cooking utensils., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Agriculture/Farms; Uniforms; Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Streets/Roads; Palm Trees; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Food; Regional/National Dress
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: A cow working a mill, a group riding a carriage, a group portrait of three women one of whom holds flower garlands., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000031; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Cattle/Cows; Transportation; Animals; Agriculture/Farms; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Head Covers/Veils; Donkeys; Carriages/Coaches; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Arabic Writing; Shops; Cigarettes; Bridges; Street Lamps; Niqab/Burqa
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000032; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: People at the Western Wall, animals grazing near the Pyramids of Giza and a sphinx., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000033; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Western Wall; Carriages/Coaches; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Rivers; Men; Women; Donkeys; Sheep; Animals; Palm Trees; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jerusalem; Palestine; Religious Sites; Canes/Walking Sticks; Transportation; Egypt; Praying
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000034; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: A man riding a camel, animals by a riverside and children in front of a dome., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000035; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Street Lamps; Camels; Goats; Animals; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Architecture; Boys; Girls; Children; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nile River; Tombs/Mausoleums
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000036; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Men and women working at riverside with baskets., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000037; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Water; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Rivers; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pottery; Nile River; Niqab/Burqa
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000038; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: A landscape of palm trees, a man fishing, and a canal running through gardens, Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000039; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Palm Trees; Men; Individual Portraits; Fishing; Canals; Gardens; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Parks; Canals
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000040; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: A landscape with buildings in the foreground, a view of men lifting barrels and train carriages, and a landscape with buildings in the foreground., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000041; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Workers; Railways; Landscapes; Egypt; Trains; Transportation; Men; Group Portraits; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000042; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Men standing next to a wreck of an air force airplane., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000043; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Airplanes; Transportation; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Deserts
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000044; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: A plane wreck, three men posing next to an airplane body in a hangar and six men standing next to a plane wreck., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000045; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Uniforms; Airplanes; Transportation; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Cars/Trucks; Police
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000046; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Men posing by a Maurice Farman S.11 Shorthorn airplane, a sarcophagus, and men standing by boats., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000047; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Uniforms; Airplanes; Transportation; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Group Portraits; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Smoking; Bridges; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Buildings; Coffins/Caskets; Tobacco pipes
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000048; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: The wreck of a tank, a group portrait of four airmen, and a boat., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000049; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Tanks; Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Weapons; Rivers
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000050; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top to bottom: Two street vendors, an aerial view of a city, and two people in front of the Great Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000051; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Pyramids; Buildings; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Camels; Men; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Animals; Palm Trees; Workers; Street Vendors; Egypt; Giza, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cemeteries; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Tea/Coffee
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000052; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top left clockwise: A man transporting supplies on donkey-back, people working in a field, two airmen, and a portrait of an airman holding a gun., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000053; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Donkeys; Animals; Agriculture/Farms; Transportation; Workers; Men; Individual Portraits; Guns; Weapons; Smoking; Cigarettes; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Water; Canals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Palm Trees; Canes/Walking Sticks
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000054; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top left clockwise: Three people standing next to a structure made of natural materials, a man riding a camel, an airman standing in front of a stone structure and a portrait of a man wearing a turban., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000055; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Cattle/Cows; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Animals; Camels; Transportation; Individual Portraits; Turbans; Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Agriculture/Farms
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000056; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top left clockwise: Men standing by the frame of an airplane, a view of clouds taken from a biplane, a man standing in front of Pharaonic statues and a ancient Egyptian stela., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000057; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Airplanes; Transportation; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Air Force; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Palm Trees
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000058; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top left clockwise: A portrait of three soldiers, a portrait of a soldier, a veiled woman standing in a street, and a man two carrying waterskins at a riverside., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000059; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Air Force; Men; Group Portraits; Guns; Weapons; Water; Individual Portraits; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Streets/Roads; Children; Boys; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Facial Hair; Workers; Niqab/Burqa; Medals/Insignia
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000060; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top left clockwise: The statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps in Port Said, palm trees lining a canal, date palms, and a man working with crops., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000061; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Statues/Sculptures; Port Said, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Group Portraits; Monuments/Memorials; Palm Trees; Canals; Individual Portraits; Workers; Agriculture/Farms; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Lesseps, Ferdinand de (Marie, Comte), 1805-1894
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000062; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- From top left clockwise: A man using a machine to make a tarboush/fez, an animal in a pen, a street scene, and a railway leading to the Great Pyramids., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000063; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Animals; Zoos; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Railways; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Machines; Streets/Roads; Street Vendors; Children; Women; Group Portraits; Donkeys; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Mosques; Architecture; Religious Sites; Workers; Shops; Millinery/Milliners; Hats
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000064; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Four portraits of women and girls., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000065; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Women; Girls; Children; Regional/National Dress; Jewelry; Food; Head Covers/Veils
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000066; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Four portraits of women., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000067; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Costumes; Clocks/Watches; Buildings; Jewelry; Egypt; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Niqab/Burqa
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000068; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Three portraits of women and a portrait of a boy on a donkey., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000069; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Women; Head Covers/Veils; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Studio Photography; Donkeys; Transportation; Animals; Boys; Children; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Pottery
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000070; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Top: A man riding a donkey. Bottom: A horse walking on a track between fields., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000071; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Donkeys; Horses; Animals; Transportation; Palm Trees; Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000072; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- A portrait of a man wearing a keffiya and agal., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000073; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Egypt
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000074; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
- Left: A portrait of a woman with a child. Right: A portrait of a man ironing., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000075; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)
  Women; Children; Girls; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Men; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Jewelry; Workers; Niqab/Burqa
- An empty page., Circa 1910-1918; nyuad_pa000004_n000076; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_014)